Jeffry Wainwright

Senior Software Engineer | Engineering Manager

Los Angeles, CA | 608. 658.1674 | yowainwright@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeffrywainwright/

Github: https://github.com/yowainwright/

Website: https://jeffry.in/about/

As a Senior Software Engineer, I specialize in frontend applications and build pipelines. Since stepping into Software Engineering Management, my focus is code re-usability and standards. I aim to keep products simple and tested—except for the "special sauce" that makes a great product exceptional. I seek roles where I can be a team's momentum multiplier while building products that make businesses happy and customers even happier.

Experience

Currency

Engineering Manager / February 2020-present

- Architected a payment platform allowing our vendors' customers to purchase large-cost items online using credit, check, or financing!
- Led the effort of building a monorepo that supports both frontend and backend ecosystems so our team can collaborate more closely and release code more safely.
- We're currently working on internationalization and few other features I'm excited to announce!
- Our tech stack is Node on the backend and React on the frontend using TypeScript in both environments.

Dollar Shave Club

Frontend Software Engineer / March 2016-February 2020

- Led the Dynamic Landing Page engineering effort, supporting internationalization and easy marketing updates using TypeScript, React, Node, and Contentful
- Contributed to Dollar Shave Club's CI/CD pipeline using Circle CI and Node, released es-check, and did a talk at JS.LA about CI/CD
- Built the analytics data layer providing accurate data in Adobe DTM
- Architected a headless CMS for Dollar Shave Club's Original Content using JavaScript, Sass, Handlebars, Codelgniter, and WordPress
- While working at Dollar Shave Club, I was key in our Engineering Marketing Strategy writing several popular open-source projects: **Reframe.js**, **Scrolldir**, **Shave**, **StickyBits**, **ES Check**

Prometheus Global Media (Hollywood Reporter/ Billboard)

Frontend Software Engineer / May 2014-March 2016

- Developed the future of UX for The Hollywood Reporter and Billboard leading to 15% readership growth and 13% decrease in bounce rate
- Built a modular frontend system which worked consistently for both The Hollywood Reporter and
 Billboard using Backbone, Node, Sass and JavaScript leading to a 200% increase in developer productivity
- The efforts above lead to a 2015 Webby Honoree for Billboard & The Hollywood Reporter Website
 Magazine, and the 2015 best website at the 8th annual National Arts & Entertainment Journalism
 Awards

Education

University of Wisconsin—Madison / 1993-2003

Bachelors of Science in Art

^{*}More career experience available upon request

^{*}More education available upon request